YEAR OF 1334 - HALF A YEAR SINCE
THE SHOGUNATE WAS DESTROYED
TOKIYUKI HOJO, FIRST NEW YEAR
SINCE LIVING IN HIDING IN SUWA
Slowly. Slowly.
We're almost there, my lord.
Here we are.
Wow.
What do you think, my lord?
It's all frozen.
You can play anywhere on Lake Suwa
in the winter.
Amazing…
My lord!
Are you okay, my lord?
Young Lord, you okay?
Man. That scared me.
It's been half a year since
the Kamakura shogunate was destroyed.
Tokiyuki ushered in his first new year
in Suwa.
Tumultuous times were put to rest
for the moment,
-but there were still small skirmishes.
-Young Lord! You can do it! Go, go!
Suwa's peace was bound
to be disrupted too.
Here it comes.
That phase when I can't see the future.
THE ELUSIVE
SAMURAI
SHINANO GOVERNOR'S RESIDENCE
I've obtained a new territory.
I need someone like you.
A man of great force, Shokan.
SHOKAN
I hear you were feared like a demon
because you were a scoundrel.
To say I'm a scoundrel
is taking it too far.
I've changed my ways.
Lord Sadamune, you are on the rise,
and so I have chosen to serve you.
I've been instructed
to take Suwa's territory piece by piece.
I'm the one for the job
because taking from others is
what I live for.
Is that all right, Sadamune?
KING
I need more strong men in our clan.
I can't win in these turbulent times
if I'm following warriors' codes.
Ogasawara is moving suspiciously
yet again.
Yes. The enemy seems to be spying on us
from the northern border.
KING
Send a scout!
The skilled scout has already
been sent elsewhere.
The situation on the western border
is precarious as well.
I must hide this secret from everyone.
On rare occasions,
I suddenly lose my gift of prophecy.
This is bad. I hope there's no trouble
during a time like this.
Um… What do you say the Elusive Warriors
go to scout out the area?
What?
Young Lord! You are so reliable!
Just as I would expect from
the future leader of this warrior family!
Please go, Young Lord!
-What? Wait.
-The Young Lord will be competent.
That's dangerous.
If anything were to happen,
-the Hojo bloodline could end.
-This is wonderful. Just as you'd expect!
Don't worry.
No one will suspect children on their own,
and you know better than anyone
of my ability to run away.
-Yes.
-Yeah, but…
Excellent idea! Kojiro and Ayako, you have
experience scouting a number of times,
and the local civilians will be at peace
with the well-mannered Lord Tokiyuki
in tow.
Let's go with this plan, Lord Yorishige!
Lord Yorishige!
No. If bandits kill him on the way,
the bloodline will end.
Ayako and I can protect him from bandits.
The lord can also escape with an assist
from Genba's trickery.
You called?
Well, if he gets lost in the woods,
the bloodline will end.
These past six months, I went on several
long horse rides within Suwa territory.
I can make my way back from anywhere
in Suwa!
No. What if he eats a slug
on the roadside, and a parasite kills him?
MUMBLE MUMBLE
What if he passes by a sultry woman
and dies of a nosebleed?
What if he remembers
something embarrassing from the past
-and dies of shock?
-I want to die.
What is wrong with you?
There's something up with you today,
Mr. Yorishige.
You're usually calm
when you send me to dangerous places.
We're getting nowhere.
Can we go now, Lord Moritaka?
Yes. This is currently the best option.
Remember, the Young Lord's safety
is your top priority.
-You got it.
-Understood!
Hey, wait a second! Lord Tokiyuki
isn't actually a great escape artist!
He's just a big weirdo
who gets off on running away!
That's so rude!
Now, how should we prepare to scout?
We should pack lightly.
Food for two days and
some traveling expenses should be plenty.
I want to bring as much money as possible.
Let's trick Moritaka and swindle him.
Genba, you always say things like that.
We shouldn't use
rice and money excessively.
LORD TOKIYUKI
MUST TAKE
Yorishige is staring.
He is staring with concern.
Father!
You know.
If Lord Tokiyuki starves to death,
his bloodline will end…
Let's ignore him and go.
Yeah, let's hurry!
This should be enough to keep me warm.
Shizuku's special cotton-laid kimono
is warm, of course.
Just one layer is all I need.
Lighter clothing is less suspicious
and it makes it easier to run away.
CHARCOAL
What?
Yorishige is staring.
He's staring like the owner…
NAMASTE - OPEN
SERVING CHILLED BEER
…of an empty curry restaurant.
You're acting really weird today,
Mr. Yorishige!
Well, if you freeze to death
or if there are one million enemy soldiers
waiting for you, the bloodline, you know?
Bloodline, bloodline, bloodline.
Does he have an obsession with bloodlines?
Ugh.
What was all that about?
He gets like that sometimes.
Like what?
He starts to worry and becomes irritable.
Who ate my mochi? Who?
He would fatten up with just water.
Or he would eat only sour things.
Is he pregnant or what?
What in the world is he thinking?
Who knows.
-He's always pushing me around, but…
-Lord Tokiyuki! Be careful.
It makes me kinda happy
that he's seeing me off with such worry.
NAKAYAMA MANOR
(SUWA TERRITORY'S NORTHERN POINT)
We got here just before sunset.
It seems peaceful.
Let me go over our plan.
We are still in Suwa territory,
but we don't have much information about
our location since it's on the far edge.
So first, we'll gather information
as messengers of Suwa Grand Shrine.
Tomorrow,
we'll take a look around the village.
We'll see if it looks like enemies
will come, and if so, when and how many.
If the village ever needs to be protected,
we'll figure out how many soldiers
we'll need and report back…
What is this?
We're surrounded.
What's up with this village?
Has it already fallen to the enemy?
He is a dual-wielder in his mid-teens.
When will the ones surrounding us
join the fight?
He's fast.
His swordsmanship is terrific
even at his young age.
Hey, fighting is outside
my area of expertise.
Let's get out of here while we can, brat.
Those two can only buy time
if they're up against that dual-wielder.
No, those two have gotten much stronger
since half a year ago!
Even then, their speed and strength
are completely different
from when they were training with me!
That means…
Back then…
You're doin' it, my lord!
You're winning one out of five times!
You'll regret it one day
if you're always underestimating me.
Wow.
If I keep training with you,
you'll surpass me.
I can't be too careless.
So, that means that other time, too?
Young Lord, you're good.
Our swords are locked
and you're pushing me.
It's because you've been training me.
By the time we're adults,
I might be the one protecting you.
AWWWW
I want to see a strong Young Lord soon.
There you go. One more push.
You got it. You got it.
They were both totally babying me.
You should've known right then and there.
Kojiro. Ayako.
Lord Tokiyuki's elusiveness
is not always reliable.
Because of his peaceful personality,
he lets his guard down.
And there are
plenty of attacks he still can't avoid.
Enemy attacks from seasoned war veterans,
from those with unusual powers,
or from warriors
who try to surpass the limits of humanity.
Up against those monsters,
there's no guarantee
that Lord Tokiyuki can outrun them.
So the two of you
should not let your guard down,
and you should continue
to become stronger samurai.
So you can protect the lord's life
from any enemy.
What brave and strongly devoted retainers.
If I also fight boldly, then one day…
Could it be… Shizuku?
Did you forget?
You fed me in east Shinano once.
Fubuki?
Please excuse my rudeness.
I got the sense those two were beasts,
so I thought
they were enemy spies in disguise.
-What?
My name is Fubuki.
I wander the land
looking for a lord to serve.
So you're not from this village?
Correct. Three days ago,
I stopped by to request a meal,
but I saw fighters with Ogasawara's
standards had raided this area,
so I aided the locals.
Platoons of about the same size
came three times.
I managed to defeat them,
but my supplies were almost out.
I was in a pinch
since I didn't even have a horse
to communicate with the outside world.
You took down three platoons…
And the villagers are holding
torches, waiting and watching?
Letting a young outsider fight?
How cowardly.
Oh, don't think lowly of them.
When I got here,
all the adults were killed.
They're all young children?
You defeated the enemy three times
all on your own?
No,
-these ones come in handy in battle, too.
-There they are!
For example,
they distract the enemy with torches.
Just you wait!
And they dig pitfalls.
They shoot the enemy
while using straw men as bait.
Even young children can learn to fight
in many ways if only you teach them.
I've been accumulating knowledge
and polishing my skills.
I'm looking for a strong lord
who will put these skills to use.
Although, I think it suits me better
to find and develop talent in others.
If only I could find a lord
who is in need of instruction…
How wonderful.
HAND COMES OUT FROM THROAT
This village is the most vital location
for Suwa?
That's the first I've heard that.
It's just that no one's realized it yet.
The population of this village is small,
but it's a hard place to corner.
If there are a hundred guards,
it morphs into an invincible fort.
NAKAYAMA MANOR
If Ogasawara were to occupy it
and place an army,
then if he were to invade
from the borders,
he would have a great advantage.
ASADA MANOR - SUWA TERRITORY
OGASAWARA
He could perform a two-front attack
on Suwa's Asada Manor,
a bountiful and large settlement.
In the art of war, it's called
a two-pronged attack.
If this were to happen,
Suwa would lose
a large portion of its territory.
BUDDHA
It seems the one
who will command the Ogasawara army
fully understands this art of war.
I thought that by communicating
the military value of this village,
my reward for protecting it would be huge.
Putting that aside, you sure do eat a lot!
Also, don't use rice to plan strategy.
Fubuki, you ate the village supply of food
in three days.
What?
Yes. So I thought I've reached my limit
of protecting the village.
Here's the source of the village crisis.
Your eye for strategy is amazing,
but you can't calculate
how much food to eat.
I wonder if it's because it's cold.
I can't seem to warm up
no matter how much I eat.
Speaking of which, I remember
when I first met you, Fubuki.
You had snuck in
and eaten all the offerings.
I had convinced our god that
a bear had snuck in,
but it was troublesome.
He was crying from how hungry he was.
I wanted to eat abalone.
I'm really sorry about that time.
At any rate, I can't say no
to an empty stomach or to a small child.
I have no dignity.
Big Brother?
Well, I thought he was
a rather calm and collected tactician,
but he's surprisingly a clumsy person.
A tactician would only be concerned
with winning.
They wouldn't go through the trouble
of trying to protect a village
with only small children.
He's the one that rallied the children and
empowered them to protect their village.
The children have just lost their parents,
but their eyes sparkle
with the will to fight.
I want his help to reclaim the throne!
I also want Fubuki
to secretly teach me to fight
so that Kojiro and Ayako
will look at me with respect!
By the way, Big Brother.
-I'm wondering why Father…
-The future.
…was strangely worried.
The future!
He may not be able to see a future
where you are safe.
No matter how important this village is,
your life is too.
I suggest we abandon the village
for now and run away,
taking the children somewhere safe
in Suwa territory.
No. I want to protect the village too,
if I can help it.
It seems the children's parents
haven't had a proper burial yet.
It's a bit much for them to lose
their home and their parents all at once.
I want them to be able to stay here
while their hearts find peace.
Big Brother…
Fubuki.
Will you let us aid you with your battle?
I would be honored if you fought with us.
Sir, won't that Sadamune guy be mad
that we killed so many villagers?
He won't mind.
It would be wrong of him to expect
morality from a former scoundrel.
On top of that…
Namu Amida Butsu.
If you say that,
Buddha will forgive all your misdeeds.
Isn't that convenient?
Buddha is the best!
The Seigi Party is composed of
only the mightiest warriors,
so it only takes five of us
to destroy one village.
On three separate ambushes,
our warriors didn't return
from that settlement.
Help me!
It doesn't seem I can drink the fine sake
of plunder by being a thief.
Let's become warriors again and fight.
EPISODE 8 (YEAR OF 1334):
A WAR OF HIDE AND SEEK
Let's go!